

Swati Thakur

Senior Systems Engineer

3+ years experienced Mainframe and Java Developer with exceptional skills in all areas of software construction and programming. Adapt at troubleshooting and ensuring quality control at every stage of management process. Able to function independently or as part of a team.

xwatithkr44@gmail.com

7591061058

Noida, India

in linkedin.com/in/swati-thakur-a02093110

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Systems Engineer Infosys Limited

10/2018 - 09/2021

Chandigarh

Tasks

- Managing and monitoring all installed systems and infrastructure.
- Installing, configuring, testing and maintaining operating systems, application software and system management tools.
- Monitoring the jobs and performing different operations on jobs according to client requirement.
- Improving the performance of a module.
- Manage development, testing and deployment of software and other computer systems technologies to ensure compliance with operational requirements for security, performance, reliability and scalability.

Senior Software Engineer Newgen Software Technology

10/2021 - Present

Noida, UP

Achievements/Tasks

- Contribute to all Stages of Software Development Lifecycle
- Design, implement and maintain Java-based applications
- Analyze user requirements to define business objectives
- Manage Java and Java EE Application Development
- Develop Documentation to help users

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Technology

University Institute of Information Technology

08/2014 - 08/2018

03/2013 - 03/2014

76

Courses

Information Technology

Higher Secondary/12th

D.A.V. Ambuja Vidya Niketan, Darlaghat

85

SKILLS

REST(Basic)

Java

Basic Python

MvSOL

COBOL

JDBC

J2EE

JSP/Servlet(Basic)

ACHIEVEMENTS

Rewarded with 100% Utilization score in current company. (08/2019 - 05/2020)

Successfully completed Infosys global training certification program. (10/2018 - 03/2019)

Awarded with Ambuja youth Scholarship for being among top 20 Students in 12th class. (08/2014 - 08/2018)

PROJECTS

Java Developer (03/2019 - 11/2019)

- Developed new application and added functionality to existing applications using Java/J2EE technologies.
- Wrote SQL gueries to retrieve data from the database using JDBC.
- Utilized frameworks such as Hibernate and Spring for persistence and application layers.

Ops Resiliency - DTCC (11/2019 - 06/2020)

- Assist in defining and coordinating team projects and activities.
- Assess and perform systems utilization and headroom reports to assist in troubleshooting and performance tuning.
- Provide status reports to direct manager and director level leadership.
- Technologies used: JCL, COBOL, CICS, DB2, VSAM.

Mainframe Developer - Charles Schwab (07/2020 - 02/2021)

- Executed cleanups from production data analysis.
- Monitored various system processes as assigned.
- Identified production issues impacting code modules.

Java Developer - OPNB (10/2021 - Present)

- Analyze the customer requirements through the SRS.
- Developing the APIs as per the requirements.
- working on Restful APIs, perform the testing.
- Maintain the issue tracker sheet.